[
    {
        "question": "managerial function that involves defining the organization's goals, establishing strategies for achieving those goals, and developing plans to integrate and coordinate work activities is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "Leading",
            "B": "Controlling",
            "C": "Planning",
            "D": "Organizing",
            "E": "Directing"
        },
        "answer": "C) Planning"
    },
    {
        "question": "company's ________\u200b spell(s) out how the organization will do what it\u200b does, how it will compete\u200b successfully, and how it will attract and satisfy customers in order to achieve its goals.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Business model",
            "B": "Mission",
            "C": "Strategies",
            "D": "Competitive advantage",
            "E": "Core competencies"
        },
        "answer": "A) Business model"
    },
    {
        "question": "of the following are reasons why strategic management is important EXCEPT\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Organizational performance",
            "B": "Organizational conflict",
            "C": "Organizational diversity",
            "D": "Organizational complexity",
            "E": "Organizational change"
        },
        "answer": "C) Organizational diversity"
    },
    {
        "question": "of the following best describes strategic\u200b management?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Strategic management is a tool that only CEOs use.",
            "B": "Strategic management is a task that managers perform to develop the\u200b company's strategies.",
            "C": "Strategic management is solely focused on the development of a competitive advantage.",
            "D": "Strategic management is focused solely on increasing revenues for the company.",
            "E": "Strategic management consists solely of the business model a company uses to carry out its functions."
        },
        "answer": "B) Strategic management is a task that managers perform to develop the\u200b company's strategies."
    },
    {
        "question": "statement is most likely true about strategic management and performance\u200b levels?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Organizations that use strategic management have higher ratings of employee satisfaction but lower performance levels.",
            "B": "There is a positive relationship between strategic management and performance.",
            "C": "Strategic management has an adverse effect on an\u200b organization's overall performance.",
            "D": "Strategic management can both raise and lower organizational performance.",
            "E": "Research has shown that strategic management has no effect on performance."
        },
        "answer": "B) There is a positive relationship between strategic management and performance."
    },
    {
        "question": "a firm intends to make money is referred to as\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Creation of value",
            "B": "Strategic management",
            "C": "Strategy",
            "D": "A business model",
            "E": "A mission"
        },
        "answer": "D) A business model"
    },
    {
        "question": "management is a key factor in helping a company to\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Focus on creating efficient internal rate of return calculations",
            "B": "Coordinate the various parts of the company to focus solely on developing financial plans",
            "C": "Create an effective public relations campaign",
            "D": "Coordinate the various parts of the organization to achieve goals",
            "E": "Develop a unique value statement"
        },
        "answer": "D) Coordinate the various parts of the organization to achieve goals"
    },
    {
        "question": "retail competitor is building a new facility within a few blocks of your store. In terms of an\u200b internal/external analysis, this would be classified as\u200b a(n) ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Opportunity",
            "B": "Resource",
            "C": "Strength",
            "D": "Threat",
            "E": "Weakness"
        },
        "answer": "D) Threat"
    },
    {
        "question": "company's brand recognition is strong. In terms of an\u200b internal/external analysis, this would be classified as\u200b a(n) ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Resource",
            "B": "Threat",
            "C": "Weakness",
            "D": "Strength",
            "E": "Opportunity"
        },
        "answer": "D) Strength"
    },
    {
        "question": "are the six steps of the strategic management\u200b process?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Mission\u200b statement, goals, marketing\u200b plans, product\u200b analysis, evaluation, and SWOT",
            "B": "Defining\u200b goals, research, cash\u200b flows, income\u200b statements, approval, and implementation",
            "C": "Identifying the\u200b mission, external\u200b analysis, internal\u200b analysis, formulating\u200b strategies, implementing\u200b strategies, and evaluating the results",
            "D": "Balancing\u200b accounts, mission\u200b statements, goals,\u200b SWOT, cash\u200b flows, and research",
            "E": "\u200bSWOT, plan\u200b approval, marketing,\u200b planning, risk\u200b assessments, and evaluating the results"
        },
        "answer": "C) Identifying the\u200b mission, external\u200b analysis, internal\u200b analysis, formulating\u200b strategies, implementing\u200b strategies, and evaluating the results"
    },
    {
        "question": "first four steps of the strategic management process involve\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Evaluations of implementation effectiveness",
            "B": "Evaluations of the effectiveness of the\u200b organization's strategies",
            "C": "Analysis for formulating strategies and defining goals",
            "D": "Marketing implementations and feedback to managers",
            "E": "The adjustments that need to be done to make the strategies successful"
        },
        "answer": "C) Analysis for formulating strategies and defining goals"
    },
    {
        "question": "conducting a SWOT\u200b analysis, a manager will most likely be able to create a strategy to\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Create a mission statement",
            "B": "Correct significant weaknesses",
            "C": "Develop marketing strategies",
            "D": "Introduce customer satisfaction initiatives",
            "E": "Develop budget initiatives"
        },
        "answer": "B) Correct significant weaknesses"
    },
    {
        "question": "the strategic management\u200b process, why is the evaluating results step so\u200b important?",
        "options": {
            "A": "To help managers compare previous strategies with current strategies",
            "B": "To calculate what\u200b managers' bonuses should be",
            "C": "To help managers determine if strategy adjustments are necessary",
            "D": "To show alignment between the\u200b company's mission and the\u200b firm's profitability",
            "E": "To show shareholders how well the company is doing"
        },
        "answer": "C) To help managers determine if strategy adjustments are necessary"
    },
    {
        "question": "________ strategy involves expansion of one or more aspects of a business.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Functional",
            "B": "Defensive",
            "C": "Stability",
            "D": "Growth",
            "E": "Renewal"
        },
        "answer": "D) Growth"
    },
    {
        "question": "terms of the BCG\u200b (Boston Consulting\u200b Group) matrix, which of the following best describes cash\u200b cows?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Low market\u200b share/low anticipated growth rate",
            "B": "High market\u200b share/low anticipated growth rate",
            "C": "High market\u200b share/high anticipated growth rate",
            "D": "Low market\u200b share/high anticipated growth rate",
            "E": "High market\u200b share/moderate anticipated growth rate"
        },
        "answer": "B) High market\u200b share/low anticipated growth rate"
    },
    {
        "question": "are the three types of corporate\u200b strategies?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u200bDiversification, concentration, and renewal",
            "B": "\u200bConcentration, innovation, and vertical integration",
            "C": "\u200bGrowth, stability, and renewal",
            "D": "\u200bVision, growth, and differentiation",
            "E": "Product\u200b development, stability, and efficient operations"
        },
        "answer": "C) \u200bGrowth, stability, and renewal"
    },
    {
        "question": "are the four methods commonly used in a growth\u200b strategy?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u200bPR, marketing, product\u200b development, and efficient manufacturing",
            "B": "\u200bRetrenchment, turnaround,\u200b exporting, and importing",
            "C": "\u200bConcentration, vertical\u200b integration, horizontal\u200b integration, and diversification",
            "D": "\u200bProduct, place,\u200b promotion, and price",
            "E": "Vertical\u200b markets, export\u200b markets, import\u200b markets, and horizontal growth"
        },
        "answer": "C) \u200bConcentration, vertical\u200b integration, horizontal\u200b integration, and diversification"
    },
    {
        "question": "statement is true about a stability\u200b strategy?",
        "options": {
            "A": "A stability strategy assumes that a company will retract some of its previous corporate initiatives.",
            "B": "A stability strategy grows its current market so the company has a more stable market share.",
            "C": "A stability strategy is when an organization continues its current strategies.",
            "D": "A stability strategy assumes that the company will exploit new markets in novel ways.",
            "E": "A stability strategy decreases corporate expenses so the business can run more efficiently."
        },
        "answer": "C) A stability strategy is when an organization continues its current strategies."
    },
    {
        "question": "are the two main types of renewal\u200b strategies?",
        "options": {
            "A": "SWOT analysis and assessment initiatives",
            "B": "Diversification and concentration",
            "C": "Retrenchment and turnaround",
            "D": "Horizontal integration and vertical integration",
            "E": "Goal orientation and evaluating the\u200b company's core values"
        },
        "answer": "C) Retrenchment and turnaround"
    },
    {
        "question": "of the following is NOT one of the five competitive forces identified by Michael\u200b Porter?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Threat of new entrants",
            "B": "Threat of substitutes",
            "C": "Anticipated legislation",
            "D": "Bargaining power of suppliers",
            "E": "Bargaining power of buyers"
        },
        "answer": "C) Anticipated legislation"
    },
    {
        "question": "company's distinctive edge is referred to as its\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Core competency",
            "B": "Corporate strategy",
            "C": "Competitive advantage",
            "D": "Mission",
            "E": "Business model"
        },
        "answer": "C) Competitive advantage"
    },
    {
        "question": "provides customers with a personal shopping assistant who helps customers track down shoes or clothing\u200b online, even if Zappos\u200b doesn't sell it. Based on this\u200b information, Zappos is most likely pursuing\u200b a(n) ________ strategy.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Customer service",
            "B": "Renewal",
            "C": "Innovation",
            "D": "First mover",
            "E": "Stability"
        },
        "answer": "A) Customer service"
    },
    {
        "question": "ABC company is focused on advancements in existing technology or services.\u200b Therefore, it is investing additional funding in research and development activities. ABC is likely pursuing\u200b a(n) ________ strategy.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u200bE-business",
            "B": "Innovation",
            "C": "Stability",
            "D": "Customer service",
            "E": "Renewal"
        },
        "answer": "B) Innovation"
    },
    {
        "question": "a sustaining competitive advantage is characterized by all of the following EXCEPT\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Exploiting a\u200b company's resources",
            "B": "Continuously improving quality",
            "C": "Accurately forecasting consumer demand",
            "D": "Using the\u200b company's core competencies",
            "E": "Increasing employee loyalty"
        },
        "answer": "C) Accurately forecasting consumer demand"
    },
    {
        "question": "is the relationship between the five competitive forces model and SWOT\u200b analysis?",
        "options": {
            "A": "The SWOT analysis looks at strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats from internal and external perspectives\u200b, while the five competitive forces model looks at competitors' market penetration\u200b and business strategies.",
            "B": "The SWOT analysis looks at market penetration\u200b strategies, and the five competitive forces model looks at external analysis of customers' needs.",
            "C": "The SWOT analysis and the five competitive forces model are both used to measure the competitive advantage in a market.",
            "D": "The five competitive forces model and SWOT analysis provide both internal and external analysis of competitors and market penetration strategies.",
            "E": "The SWOT analysis looks at internal forces and looks for opportunities\u200b, while the five competitive forces model looks at external forces and market penetration model."
        },
        "answer": "D) Five forces model and SWOT analysis"
    },
    {
        "question": "of the following is the best description of environmental\u200b scanning?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Scanning for signs of global competition",
            "B": "Scanning for potential leaders in key areas",
            "C": "Looking at competitive forces outside the company",
            "D": "Looking for political trends that may affect business models",
            "E": "Scanning external and internal factors that might impact the organization"
        },
        "answer": "E) Scanning external and internal factors that might impact the organization"
    },
    {
        "question": "monitors her\u200b competitors' blogs,\u200b posts, and websites and the Twitter messages of their\u200b CEOs, and she records dates and notes on a\u200b spreadsheet, looking for patterns. Judi is performing\u200b ________.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Competitive analysis",
            "B": "Strategic planning",
            "C": "Market research",
            "D": "Environmental scanning",
            "E": "Benchmarking"
        },
        "answer": "D) Environmental scanning"
    },
    {
        "question": "of the following primarily involves assessing information to determine emerging\u200b trends?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Competitive intelligence",
            "B": "Competitive analysis",
            "C": "Environmental scanning",
            "D": "SWOT analysis",
            "E": "Benchmarking"
        },
        "answer": "C) Environmental scanning"
    },
    {
        "question": "of the following involves collecting basic information about rival firms for the purpose of anticipating their\u200b actions?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Environmental scanning",
            "B": "Competitive intelligence",
            "C": "Benchmarking",
            "D": "Strategic forecasting",
            "E": "Market research"
        },
        "answer": "B) Competitive intelligence"
    },
    {
        "question": "statement is true about competitive\u200b intelligence?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Competitive intelligence is illegal when performed by managers at companies.",
            "B": "Competitive intelligence helps managers anticipate the competition\u2019s actions.",
            "C": "Competitive intelligence involves gathering intelligence on customer preferences only.",
            "D": "Competitive intelligence is based only on public information about a company\u2019s actions.",
            "E": "Competitive intelligence focuses solely on the operational strategies of a business."
        },
        "answer": "B) Competitive intelligence helps managers anticipate the competition\u2019s actions"
    }
]